Why don't you just give us the history, cuz I need to know.
So, a lot of times, black thangs, happy Black History Month.
Black thangs come into the mix and it seems like it's just, it's cool.
So it permeates all of pop culture.
Everybody wants to be a part of it.
But the reality is, is most things that folks think are just some cool black
things came out of innovation.
And they came out of having to figure something out when they couldn't do
something just cuz they wanted to freely.
The DAP is no exception.
So, Folk Life Magazine had an article called Five on the Black Hand Side,
Origins and Evolutions of the DAP by Lamont Hamilton.
Now, the DAP originated in the 60s among black soldiers in the Vietnam War.
Wow.
Yes, it did.
The black power movement was growing.
There was racial unrest in cities.
Young African Americans were being sent into combat and
the DAP was about unity and survival.
There were cases of black soldiers reportedly being shot by white soldiers during
combats and so it was a physical act of solidarity like, hey bruh, I see you,
you see me, watch my back out there.
Right.
It was used to convey their commitment to looking after one another.
Wow.
And it's an acronym for dignity and pride.
So the DAP was even banned in the military because folks thought it was a code for
doing a black power sign.
Wow.
Later in the war, the military saw utility of using the DAP in medical treatment of
black combatants with post-traumatic stress disorder and created a program of DAP therapy.
So, in present day when we see folks DAPing up, DAPing up, DAPing up, we have to remember-
That's the history of it.
Yes, there's a tremendous diversity of DAPs and
it came out from movements of the military company.
Wow.
Yeah, so we see it as just like, hey, what's up, what's up, but there's always a deeper meaning.